<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>BestOf - Category - smcleod.net</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/categories/bestof/</link><description>BestOf - Category - smcleod.net</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Sam McLeod</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beta.smcleod.net/categories/bestof/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Best Of - 2022 Edition</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/tools.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Near the end of each year I note down a summary of the best apps I&rsquo;ve enjoyed using throughout the year, here&rsquo;s 2022.
Info See also Firefox Addons - 2022 The Best MeetingBar (Meetings in your menubar) - Get MeetingBar Reeder (RSS) - Get Reeder Shottr (Better screenshots) - Get Shottr Bumpr (Multi-browser rules for links) - Get Bumper Onyx (macOS customisation) - Get OnyX Brew (Package manager) - Get Brew mas (Mac App Store manager for Brew) - Get mas Little Snitch (Firewall) - Get Little Snitch RadioSilence (Simple Firewall) - Get RadioSilence Pixelmator Pro (Image/Photo editor) - Get Pixelmator Pro Keka (Archive/Compression tool) - Get Keka LaunchControl (Frontend for launchd) - Get LaunchControl Peek (Quicklook plugins) - Get Peek MusicHarbor (Track new and upcoming music releases) - Get MusicHarbor DaisyDisk (Disk usage inspector) - Get DaisyDisk Things (GTD/Notes/Lists app) - Get Thing BetterTouchTool (macOS automation and customisation) - Get BetterTouchTool Parcel (Track parcels) - Get Parcel Backblaze (Backups) - Get Backblaze MicroSnitch (Get notifications for active mic/webcam) - Get Micro Snitch Handbrake (Transcode video files) - Get Handbrake Amphetamine (Keep you mac awake) - Get Amphetamine Bear (Markdown/notes/web clipping) - Get Bear Calibre (eBook management and conversation) - Get Calibre ImageOptim Beta (Image compression) - Get ImageOptim Note: This is a beta version, but it&rsquo;s the only version that supports Apple Silicon natively, the author is working on ImageOptim 2 - A complete rewrite.]]></description></item><item><title>The Best Of - 2020 Edition</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/william-hook-unsplash.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Near the end of every year I note down a summary of the best apps, hardware &amp; podcasts I&rsquo;ve enjoyed throughout the year (and often for some time before).
Info This post has been superseded. You can find the latest version of this post here. Software and Services Plex Things Pixelmator Pro Reeder NextMeeting Bumpr Fastmail 1Password Calibre Backblaze iTerm Gitlab PFsense Stay Onyx Evernote Handbrake Amphetamine Firefox Software - Mobile Plex Things Reeder Overcast Evernote MiniHack Alien Blue Singal Prompt Browser Addons uBlock Origin Dencentraleyes Hardware LG C9 OLED TV Das Ultimate 4 Logitech MX Master 3 16&rsquo;&rsquo; Macbook Pro iPhone 12 Pro AppleTV 4K Audioquest DragonFly Red USB DAC Ultrasone Signature Pro Headphones Kindle Paperwhite All Day Socks Bellroy Wallets Podcasts The Skeptics Guide To The Universion (SGU) You Are Not So Smart Risky.]]></description></item><item><title>The Best Of - 2014 Edition</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2015/02/the-best-of-2014-edition/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2015/02/the-best-of-2014-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2015/02/the-best-of-2014-edition/patrick-tomasso-71909.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>At the end of every year I note down a summary of the best applications, hardware &amp; websites I&rsquo;ve enjoyed &amp; depended on throughout the year (and often for some time before).
Info This post has long since been superseded. You can find the latest version of this post here. Software / General Use Fastmail - https://www.fastmail.com Evernote - https://evernote.com Reeder - http://reederapp.com Keynote - https://www.apple.com/au/mac/keynote Lastpass - https://lastpass.com Plex - https://plex.tv Calibre - http://calibre-ebook.com Software / Geek Use Sublime Text - http://www.sublimetext.com/3 Homebrew - http://brew.sh DropSync - http://mudflatsoftware.com Beets - http://beets.radbox.org Textual - http://www.codeux.com/textual XLD - http://tmkk.undo.jp/xld/index_e.html Code Academy - http://www.]]></description></item></channel></rss>