<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>software - Tag - smcleod.net</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/tags/software/</link><description>software - Tag - smcleod.net</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Sam McLeod</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beta.smcleod.net/tags/software/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Best Of - 2022 Edition</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/tools.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Near the end of each year I note down a summary of the best apps I&rsquo;ve enjoyed using throughout the year, here&rsquo;s 2022.
Info See also Firefox Addons - 2022 The Best MeetingBar (Meetings in your menubar) - Get MeetingBar Reeder (RSS) - Get Reeder Shottr (Better screenshots) - Get Shottr Bumpr (Multi-browser rules for links) - Get Bumper Onyx (macOS customisation) - Get OnyX Brew (Package manager) - Get Brew mas (Mac App Store manager for Brew) - Get mas Little Snitch (Firewall) - Get Little Snitch RadioSilence (Simple Firewall) - Get RadioSilence Pixelmator Pro (Image/Photo editor) - Get Pixelmator Pro Keka (Archive/Compression tool) - Get Keka LaunchControl (Frontend for launchd) - Get LaunchControl Peek (Quicklook plugins) - Get Peek MusicHarbor (Track new and upcoming music releases) - Get MusicHarbor DaisyDisk (Disk usage inspector) - Get DaisyDisk Things (GTD/Notes/Lists app) - Get Thing BetterTouchTool (macOS automation and customisation) - Get BetterTouchTool Parcel (Track parcels) - Get Parcel Backblaze (Backups) - Get Backblaze MicroSnitch (Get notifications for active mic/webcam) - Get Micro Snitch Handbrake (Transcode video files) - Get Handbrake Amphetamine (Keep you mac awake) - Get Amphetamine Bear (Markdown/notes/web clipping) - Get Bear Calibre (eBook management and conversation) - Get Calibre ImageOptim Beta (Image compression) - Get ImageOptim Note: This is a beta version, but it&rsquo;s the only version that supports Apple Silicon natively, the author is working on ImageOptim 2 - A complete rewrite.]]></description></item><item><title>Firefox Addons for 2022</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/05/firefox-addons-for-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/05/firefox-addons-for-2022/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2022/05/firefox-addons-for-2022/firefox-logo-collage-1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Firefox Addons - 2022 EditionMy list of must-have Firefox addons - 2022 edition
Updated: 2022-10-09
Privacy and SecurityFirstly - you should have Firefox&rsquo;s Enhanced Tracking Protection enabled.
Don&rsquo;t Track Me Google LocalCDN UTM Tracking Token Stripper Note: You can accomplish some of what this does by setting up the removeparam uBlock origin rules I&rsquo;ve listed below. Multi-Account Containers Useful for setting sites such as Amazon, eBay, Twitter, LinkedIn, Banking etc&hellip; each to always open in their own isolated container. The official addon for whatever Password Manager you use. Firefox Translations uBlock OriginProbably the single most important addon.
uBlock Origin Enable and update all built-int filter lists except for &lsquo;Regions&rsquo; and &lsquo;Languages&rsquo;.]]></description></item><item><title>Goodbye Evernote, Hello Bear</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2021/07/goodbye-evernote-hello-bear/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2021/07/goodbye-evernote-hello-bear/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2021/07/goodbye-evernote-hello-bear/bear_header-mac-screenshot.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Until recently I used Evernote for my notes, web clippings and document drafts, I was a subscriber going on 14 years and had over 3000 notes.
However in recent years Evernote has gone downhill to the point it could be considered hostile to it&rsquo;s users.
The native macOS app was replaced with an Electron Javascript webframe and like almost all Electron apps I&rsquo;ve tried it was plagued by poor performance, memory leaks and aggressive idle CPU utilisation and above all else it now lacks the low latency feeling the native application had.
With the release of the updated client, Evernote has removed offline note functionality - tough luck if you&rsquo;re travelling or don&rsquo;t have reliable internet access.]]></description></item><item><title>The Best Of - 2020 Edition</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/william-hook-unsplash.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Near the end of every year I note down a summary of the best apps, hardware &amp; podcasts I&rsquo;ve enjoyed throughout the year (and often for some time before).
Info This post has been superseded. You can find the latest version of this post here. Software and Services Plex Things Pixelmator Pro Reeder NextMeeting Bumpr Fastmail 1Password Calibre Backblaze iTerm Gitlab PFsense Stay Onyx Evernote Handbrake Amphetamine Firefox Software - Mobile Plex Things Reeder Overcast Evernote MiniHack Alien Blue Singal Prompt Browser Addons uBlock Origin Dencentraleyes Hardware LG C9 OLED TV Das Ultimate 4 Logitech MX Master 3 16&rsquo;&rsquo; Macbook Pro iPhone 12 Pro AppleTV 4K Audioquest DragonFly Red USB DAC Ultrasone Signature Pro Headphones Kindle Paperwhite All Day Socks Bellroy Wallets Podcasts The Skeptics Guide To The Universion (SGU) You Are Not So Smart Risky.]]></description></item><item><title>Goodbye XenSever - Hello XCP-ng</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/02/goodbye-xensever-hello-xcp-ng/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/02/goodbye-xensever-hello-xcp-ng/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/2019/02/goodbye-xensever-hello-xcp-ng/xcpng_rocket_logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>In 2018 I set out to replace our XenSever 7.2 based virtualisation after Citrix essentially screwed over free / open source users.
This project was to directly replace XenServer 7.2 with something supported and manageable for our traditional virtualisation needs.
High Level Selection ConsiderationsI evaluated a number of options, with the primary candidates below.
Key criteria (at a high level) I was evaluating:
Ease of moving from our existing XenServer 7.2 based hypervisor clusters. Security (architecture, hardening, monitoring, logging). Cost (both licensing if any and self-support / management costs). VM Performance (Storage IOPs and throughput, Network latency and throughput, Processing latency, steal from over-provisioned workloads).</description></item><item><title>Run youtube-dl (or similar) in the background</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/run-youtube-dl-or-similar-in-the-background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/run-youtube-dl-or-similar-in-the-background/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2018/07/run-youtube-dl-or-similar-in-the-background/camera-background.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I wanted an alias or function to use youtube-dl in the background. Looking around the web lots of people seemed to want this and most of them were banging their heads against a wall due to:
A) bash quoting B) backgrounding dying when their terminal closed C) passing the argument (url in my case) to the function Here&rsquo;s a simple function I whipped up that seems to &lsquo;just works&rsquo;™:
function yt { nohup youtube-dl &#34;$1&#34; --no-progress 2&gt;&amp;1 &gt; youtube-dl-&#34;$(date +%Y%m%d-%H%M%S)&#34;.log &amp; } And if you don&rsquo;t want logs, simply send the output to /dev/null:
function yt { nohup youtube-dl &#34;$1&#34; --no-progress 2&gt;&amp;1 &gt; /dev/null &amp; } Example:]]></description></item><item><title>Disabling scroll-wheel zoom in Firefox</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/disabling-scroll-wheel-zoom-in-firefox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 10:57:14 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/disabling-scroll-wheel-zoom-in-firefox/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2018/07/disabling-scroll-wheel-zoom-in-firefox/zoom.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>This feature annoys me endlessly, I end up zoomed in and out of websites all over the internet. &hellip; But the fix is easy and there&rsquo;s no addons required.
Navigate to about:config (in Firefox&rsquo;s URL bar) Change the value of the following two properties to 0: mousewheel.with_control.action mousewheel.with_meta.action If you use Firefox sync and want these settings to sync between your machines, also add the following properties:
Create two new properties both of type boolean and set them to true:
services.sync.prefs.sync.mousewheel.with_meta.action services.sync.prefs.sync.mousewheel.with_control.action Enjoy!]]></description></item><item><title>GlusterFS</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2017/09/glusterfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2017/09/glusterfs/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2017/09/glusterfs/backdrop-insidebuilding.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>We&rsquo;re in the process of shifting from using our custom &lsquo;glue&rsquo; for orchestrating Docker deployments to Kubernetes, When we first deployed Docker to replace LXC and our legacy Puppet-heavy application configuration and deployment systems there really wasn&rsquo;t any existing tool to manage this, thus we rolled our own, mainly a few Ruby scripts combined with a Puppet / Hiera / Mcollective driven workflow.
The main objective is to replace our legacy NFS file servers used to host uploads / attachments and static files for our web applications, while NFS(v4) performance is adequate, it is a clear single point of failure and of course, there are the age old stale mount problems should network interruptions occur.]]></description></item><item><title>Return Of The RSS</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2017/09/return-of-the-rss/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2017/09/return-of-the-rss/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2017/09/return-of-the-rss/melbourne.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Of all the tools for reading news and subscribing to software releases, I still find RSS the most useful.
I use Feedly to manage my rss subscriptions and keep all my devices in sync, but instead of using the Feedly&rsquo;s own client, I use an app called Reeder as the client / reader itself.
Link: My Feedly RSS Feed FeedlyRSS feed subscription management
Features:
Keyword alerts. Browser plugins to subscribe to (current) url. Notation and highlighting support (a bit like Evernote). Search and filtering across large numbers of feeds / content. IFTTT, Zapier, Buffer and Hootsuite integration. Built in save / share functionality (that I only use when I&rsquo;m on the website).]]></description></item><item><title>Monitoring SystemD Units With Nagios</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2016/05/monitoring-systemd-units-with-nagios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2016/05/monitoring-systemd-units-with-nagios/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2016/05/monitoring-systemd-units-with-nagios/feature-laptop.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Ever forgotten to add a critical service to monitoring?
Want to know if a service or process fails without explicitly monitoring every service on a host?
&hellip;Then why not use SystemD&rsquo;s existing knowledge of all the enabled services? Thanks to &lsquo;Kbyte&rsquo; who made a simple Nagios plugin to do just this!
Requirements Python3 (For RHEL/CentOS 7 yum install python34) python-nagiosplugin My pre-built RPMs or pip3 install nagiosplugin PyNagSystemD ]]></description></item></channel></rss>