<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Tech - Category - smcleod.net</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/categories/tech/</link><description>Tech - Category - smcleod.net</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Sam McLeod</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beta.smcleod.net/categories/tech/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making Work Visible - Avoid DMs</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/making-work-visible-avoid-dms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/making-work-visible-avoid-dms/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2022/10/making-work-visible-avoid-dms/dm-disruption.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Avoid sending DMs/PMs for support and technical questionsThis is a blurb I usually add to the wiki pages of teams I work with, it&rsquo;s a simple reminder that we should avoid sending direct messages (or worse - calling) individuals for support and technical questions.
Instead, we should use the appropriate channels for the team. This is a simple way to make work visible, share knowledge, reduce context switching, avoid silos and share the support load
Avoid sending DMs/PMs for support and technical questions We value making work visiblePart of this is achieved by us making an effort to ensure we&rsquo;re asking for support and technical questions by starting a thread in our squads (or the relevant) room - instead of via of direct messaging (or calling) an individual.]]></description></item><item><title>The Best Of - 2022 Edition</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2022/10/the-best-of-2022-edition/tools.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Near the end of each year I note down a summary of the best apps I&rsquo;ve enjoyed using throughout the year, here&rsquo;s 2022.
Info See also Firefox Addons - 2022 The Best MeetingBar (Meetings in your menubar) - Get MeetingBar Reeder (RSS) - Get Reeder Shottr (Better screenshots) - Get Shottr Bumpr (Multi-browser rules for links) - Get Bumper Onyx (macOS customisation) - Get OnyX Brew (Package manager) - Get Brew mas (Mac App Store manager for Brew) - Get mas Little Snitch (Firewall) - Get Little Snitch RadioSilence (Simple Firewall) - Get RadioSilence Pixelmator Pro (Image/Photo editor) - Get Pixelmator Pro Keka (Archive/Compression tool) - Get Keka LaunchControl (Frontend for launchd) - Get LaunchControl Peek (Quicklook plugins) - Get Peek MusicHarbor (Track new and upcoming music releases) - Get MusicHarbor DaisyDisk (Disk usage inspector) - Get DaisyDisk Things (GTD/Notes/Lists app) - Get Thing BetterTouchTool (macOS automation and customisation) - Get BetterTouchTool Parcel (Track parcels) - Get Parcel Backblaze (Backups) - Get Backblaze MicroSnitch (Get notifications for active mic/webcam) - Get Micro Snitch Handbrake (Transcode video files) - Get Handbrake Amphetamine (Keep you mac awake) - Get Amphetamine Bear (Markdown/notes/web clipping) - Get Bear Calibre (eBook management and conversation) - Get Calibre ImageOptim Beta (Image compression) - Get ImageOptim Note: This is a beta version, but it&rsquo;s the only version that supports Apple Silicon natively, the author is working on ImageOptim 2 - A complete rewrite.]]></description></item><item><title>The Best Of - 2020 Edition</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2020/10/the-best-of-2020-edition/william-hook-unsplash.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Near the end of every year I note down a summary of the best apps, hardware &amp; podcasts I&rsquo;ve enjoyed throughout the year (and often for some time before).
Info This post has been superseded. You can find the latest version of this post here. Software and Services Plex Things Pixelmator Pro Reeder NextMeeting Bumpr Fastmail 1Password Calibre Backblaze iTerm Gitlab PFsense Stay Onyx Evernote Handbrake Amphetamine Firefox Software - Mobile Plex Things Reeder Overcast Evernote MiniHack Alien Blue Singal Prompt Browser Addons uBlock Origin Dencentraleyes Hardware LG C9 OLED TV Das Ultimate 4 Logitech MX Master 3 16&rsquo;&rsquo; Macbook Pro iPhone 12 Pro AppleTV 4K Audioquest DragonFly Red USB DAC Ultrasone Signature Pro Headphones Kindle Paperwhite All Day Socks Bellroy Wallets Podcasts The Skeptics Guide To The Universion (SGU) You Are Not So Smart Risky.]]></description></item><item><title>Looking For New Opportunities</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/08/looking-for-new-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/08/looking-for-new-opportunities/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2019/08/looking-for-new-opportunities/fiji_aws_prac_training_1.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>As stated in my announcement post - after 7~ years, I resigned from Infoxchange several months ago.
I planned on taking a holiday, relaxing, decompressing, dipping my toes in some off-the-shelf tech I haven&rsquo;t spent a lot of time with and performing some personal growth through reading a number of books that have been sitting on my &rsquo;to read&rsquo; shelf.
This is exactly what I&rsquo;ve done.
I&rsquo;m now open to new opportunitiesI&rsquo;d rather find a workplace that I can add great value too and be happy to work with than rush into a new role quickly, obviously if something great turns up right away - I&rsquo;ll pursue it.]]></description></item><item><title>Leaving Infoxchange</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/06/leaving-infoxchange/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/06/leaving-infoxchange/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2019/06/leaving-infoxchange/road-no-car-2048.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>After 7~ years, I have resigned from Infoxchange.
In 2012 I was hired to work with Infoxchange to &ldquo;shake things up&rdquo; (in the Systems Operations team) and stabilise the hosting environment.
As Team Lead of Systems Operations I was tasked with melding the team and then for us to work to provide a stable, robust, modern and scalable platform for Infoxchange developed application hosting and product delivery and in a short time, with a small budget - we did just that.
This 7~ year journey was exciting, rewarding and of course at times very stressful.
I have learnt a lot and made so many very dear friends so resigning was far from easy, however it is time to move forward to new potential challenges.]]></description></item><item><title>Goodbye XenSever - Hello XCP-ng</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/02/goodbye-xensever-hello-xcp-ng/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2019/02/goodbye-xensever-hello-xcp-ng/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/2019/02/goodbye-xensever-hello-xcp-ng/xcpng_rocket_logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>In 2018 I set out to replace our XenSever 7.2 based virtualisation after Citrix essentially screwed over free / open source users.
This project was to directly replace XenServer 7.2 with something supported and manageable for our traditional virtualisation needs.
High Level Selection ConsiderationsI evaluated a number of options, with the primary candidates below.
Key criteria (at a high level) I was evaluating:
Ease of moving from our existing XenServer 7.2 based hypervisor clusters. Security (architecture, hardening, monitoring, logging). Cost (both licensing if any and self-support / management costs). VM Performance (Storage IOPs and throughput, Network latency and throughput, Processing latency, steal from over-provisioned workloads).</description></item><item><title>Run youtube-dl (or similar) in the background</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/run-youtube-dl-or-similar-in-the-background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/run-youtube-dl-or-similar-in-the-background/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2018/07/run-youtube-dl-or-similar-in-the-background/camera-background.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I wanted an alias or function to use youtube-dl in the background. Looking around the web lots of people seemed to want this and most of them were banging their heads against a wall due to:
A) bash quoting B) backgrounding dying when their terminal closed C) passing the argument (url in my case) to the function Here&rsquo;s a simple function I whipped up that seems to &lsquo;just works&rsquo;™:
function yt { nohup youtube-dl &#34;$1&#34; --no-progress 2&gt;&amp;1 &gt; youtube-dl-&#34;$(date +%Y%m%d-%H%M%S)&#34;.log &amp; } And if you don&rsquo;t want logs, simply send the output to /dev/null:
function yt { nohup youtube-dl &#34;$1&#34; --no-progress 2&gt;&amp;1 &gt; /dev/null &amp; } Example:]]></description></item><item><title>Disabling scroll-wheel zoom in Firefox</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/disabling-scroll-wheel-zoom-in-firefox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 10:57:14 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/07/disabling-scroll-wheel-zoom-in-firefox/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2018/07/disabling-scroll-wheel-zoom-in-firefox/zoom.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>This feature annoys me endlessly, I end up zoomed in and out of websites all over the internet. &hellip; But the fix is easy and there&rsquo;s no addons required.
Navigate to about:config (in Firefox&rsquo;s URL bar) Change the value of the following two properties to 0: mousewheel.with_control.action mousewheel.with_meta.action If you use Firefox sync and want these settings to sync between your machines, also add the following properties:
Create two new properties both of type boolean and set them to true:
services.sync.prefs.sync.mousewheel.with_meta.action services.sync.prefs.sync.mousewheel.with_control.action Enjoy!]]></description></item><item><title>Flash Storage and SSD Failure Rate Update (March 2018)</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/03/flash-storage-and-ssd-failure-rate-update-march-2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/03/flash-storage-and-ssd-failure-rate-update-march-2018/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2018/03/flash-storage-and-ssd-failure-rate-update-march-2018/sam-standing-at-rack.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>It was almost 3 years ago that my open source storage project went into production. In that time it&rsquo;s been running 24/7 serving as highly available solid state storage for hundreds of VMs and several virtualisation clusters across our two main sites.
I&rsquo;m happy to report that the clusters have been operating very successfully since their conception.
Since moving away from proprietary &lsquo;black box&rsquo; vendor SANs, we haven&rsquo;t had a single SAN issue, storage outage.
We&rsquo;ve also been so please with the success of the design that we&rsquo;ve grown from a single cluster at each site to a total of 6 clusters (12 nodes).]]></description></item><item><title>Theory of constraints</title><link>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/01/theory-of-constraints/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Sam McLeod</name></author><guid>https://beta.smcleod.net/2018/01/theory-of-constraints/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/2018/01/theory-of-constraints/samuel-zeller-237359.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>&ldquo;A chain is no stronger than its weakest link&rdquo; Any improvement made anywhere besides the bottleneck is an illusion.
Any improvement made after the bottleneck is useless because it will always remain starved waiting for work from the bottleneck.
Any improvement made before the bottleneck merely results in more ‘work&rsquo; piling up at the bottleneck.
Identify the system&rsquo;s constraint(s) (that which prevents the organisation from obtaining more of the goal in a unit of time) Decide how to exploit the system&rsquo;s constraint(s) (how to get the most out of the constraint) Subordinate everything else to the above decision (align the whole system or organization to support the decision made above) Elevate the system&rsquo;s constraint(s) (make other major changes needed to increase the constraint&rsquo;s capacity) Warning!]]></description></item></channel></rss>